Doan Thi Kieu Oanh

DATA ANALYST

Under the control of the control of

BACKGROUND/CAREER OBJECTIVES

I have nearly 2 years of experience in the Data industry. In addition to professional skills, I am also a young person who always tries my best to achieve the goals he sets in his work and career. With the skills, experience and spirit of always wanting to learn, I always try to devote my best and ensure work on 3 criteria: ACTIVITY - RESPONSIBILITY - COMMITMENT

EDUCATION

2019 - 2023
2022 - 2023

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cennos, Inc. 8/2021 - 8/2022

Data Entry Clerk

- Enter data, filter, edit and update product information on Excel and spreadsheet files.
- Update display images and AI on foreign e-commerce stores.
- Respond to customer emails in English about product information as it arises

Novaon Group 8/2022 - 12/2022

Talent Acquisition Intern

- Carry out recruitment activities for each department. Build sources and filter candidate information.
- Contact, discuss and arrange interview schedules at the request of the department head.
- Support the team to input candidate data into the Database. Make reports on recruitment status as required
- Contribute creative ideas to Employee Branding on Social platforms
- Make reports on the Team's Employee Branding development on Excel files, Google Sheets and Data Visualization on Power BI

FiinGroup 5/2023 - Present

Data Processing Specialist

- Led a team of 3 members and supervised 6-8 interns responsible for updating and maintaining a database of over 1 million Vietnamese enterprises, encompassing both public and private companies.
- Managed corporate profiles, financial data, corporate activities, import and export activities, as well as data on tax and insurance debts.
- Controlled and implemented the process of moving raw data to the database using SMSS, Database, Microsoft SQL, and ETL.
- Engineered and executed a data update and integration plan, significantly reducing data lag time from 3 months to 1 month.
- Established a data quality control system to enhance data accuracy, decreasing significant errors from 7% to below 3%.
- Cleaned data, identified, and rectified data issues, resulting in a 30% improvement in data consistency.

- Collaborated with 3 internal departments to streamline data requirements and documentation, thereby expediting data updates for 3 main analytical platforms.
- Executed SQL queries to extract financial report information, corporate finances, and business details as required by customers (Datafeed Project, API custom project).
- Utilized SQL, Power BI, and Excel (along with VBA and macros) to design and deploy a monthly Workforce Management Dashboard for a team of 20 analysts and each data group's personnel.
- Conducted analysis and developed tools using Python to automate and optimize the data processing process for various data sources such as Taxfee Debt, Insurance Debt, and Negative Business News.
- This optimization resulted in a more than 70% reduction in data processing time, diminishing reliance on human resources.
- Contributed to analyzing, evaluating, and preparing data for input variables of the business credit rating model for over 2,000 active Vietnamese enterprises.

• Regularly maintained and updated Data Flow documents, Mapping documents, and Rules on data processing procedures between systems to facilitate data ingestion and data solution services. **ACTIVITIES** Liên chi đoàn Khoa kinh tế và Quản lý nguồn nhân lực 2019 - 2021 Tiểu ban kĩ thuật - ban truyền thông **CERTIFICATIONS** MOS 2022 9Slide 2021 **TOEIC (765)** 2023 **HACKERRANK** SQL (Advanced) Skill Certification Test SQL (Intermediate) Skill Certification T **SKILLS** Excel 9/10 **SQL** 9/10 6/10 Python Power BI 8/10 **Statistics** 7/10

INTERESTS

Reading, Listen to mucsic, singing, playing sports